This is traditional fishing in Colombia.
This is not a fishing charter. These are
two guys that fish for their meal every
day with hand lines in a tiny little
boat. Like this is what they do. This is
how they eat.
This is not your average fishing guide,
dude. This is real life.
And this is a little beach town we're
at.
It's not really a town, it's more of a
village. Let me tell you, Taganga
is the most
old town. The second old city in
America.
The first city of Colombia
Santa Marta. But the Spanish arriving in
Taganga first. Should have kicked them
out.
How?
Yeah. [__] happens. We're in a little
town called Taganga. Taganga.
It's fantastic, dude. Good vibe.
Beautiful weather. Um, let's see if we
can go catch some fish. That's what we
wanted to use, the poles back there.
Or these. And of course, what did we
say? Yeah, we want to try the things.
This is how we're trolling right now.
Uh
They gave me this thing
and we're riding around.
I'm telling you
if a big tuna hit that, it's going to
snatch my arm. This is like a
traditional village, it's just
modernized a bit, isn't it? Well, I
wouldn't even say that modernized
because it's still very traditional
fishing village, as you can see. Yeah. I
mean, look at the boat. Look at the
people. Look at the anchor.
All right.
>> [laughter]
>> These are pretty big waves and we're in
a tiny boat. Wouldn't you agree? Yes.
I mean, it's absolutely fantastic when
you look at it.
We have an old spark plug right here
that's going to be used as a weight.
Bringing up a line.
We're
These are actual local fishermen. Like
this is what they do. This is how they
eat.
And the spark plug weight is my favorite
thing ever. Right now I'm the stupid
American filming and tying a spark plug
on a fishing line, but I love this [__]
Don't hate it, appreciate it. See?
All right.
My turn.
So, it's my first hand line fish ever.
Help. Watch out. Don't go stick your
hand in there.
Oh boy.
Got the hard way. Grouper, I think.
That's a little baby grouper. You see
that? They sit under water with that
little thing right there and wiggle it
like a worm and something goes in there,
chomp.
You get to go back to daycare, fishes.
We are pulled up right now by these rock
structures. All right.
My first fish.
He's got to get ate today, don't he?
Yeah, good catch, homie.
That looks like a vermilion snapper to
me.
Round two.
We are dropping anchor.
We're going to go on the beach and I
think we're going to try and harpoon
some [__]
This is where we are now. Look how
gorgeous the water is. This is the
little fishing shack that we stopped at.
It's pretty cool.
And then
there's this building up here.
Let's go take a look.
Whoa.
I don't know what they got this
driftwood for, but uh maybe it's a
shutter.
We're in a little hammock.
And I guess this would be the kitchen.
Holy hell.
All they got's a little brick wall right
here to keep the wind out. I don't know
about you, but I would be happy living
like this as long as I had the people I
loved around me and plenty of fish.
That's it.
Mhm.
You have a center Ricardo giving me a
harpoon and instructions to go shoot a
fish.
So, that's what I'm going to do. I've
only been spearfishing one time in my
life and it was in St. Lucia with some
Rastas. And uh this is much the same.
It's a harpoon. No life jacket. No real
instructions other than don't die and
come back with a fish.
Epa. I really want to shoot one more.
I think there's a ton of fish in there
and all I want to do is go shoot one.
But then they swim away. I go up there
and catch them on the rocks cuz they
hang out on these big rocks.
And man, I come around the bend and
there was a whole school of them pink
yellow fish and I shot me one of the
parts.
I could do this absolutely all day.
Got him.
I tell you I could do this
absolutely all day long. You have to
shoot two fish and you can eat all day.
What do you think?
Nice. I just got out of the water. How
long was I in there? Hour? I don't About
an hour. I shot two fish. It's a whole
lot of fun, man. There's fish all in the
water. Like there's tons of fish, but
it's really hard to shoot them. They
don't have to swim
like really fast, just a little bit
deeper and you run out of air. But man,
I could literally do this all day long.
He is starting to clean the catch right
now.
That's that little guy shot on the
beach. Hey.
Is this Is it the same one? No. It's the
same one. He He doesn't have that labia.
We are wrapping up for the day.
Going back. We got four in the boat.
It has been a fantastic day having us,
Sebastian. Yes, it has. This is today's
catch.
He's putting it on a stringer for us.
And we got five little fish right here.
Look like some snapper, maybe a pargo.
I'm not exactly sure. So, this is Bruno,
he's the guy who set this up. How long
has it been since you've eaten fish? 7
years. And you caught this yourself? I
caught one. I caught that one. It's
okay. Dad, you better eat that one then.
All right. All right.
Put a little lime on that guy.
Oh, wow.
What do you think?
I missed it. Good? Yes. Perfecto, no?
All right. I'm going to try the pargo.
The pargo fish is the most yummy one.
All right. Little bit of
lime on there.
You know, it's fantastic.
No fishy taste whatsoever.
Crispy fried.
A little bit of salt, some lime.
It just tastes like it's good for you.
If you've never been to Colombia, you've
got to change that. This place is a
hidden gem. Now, how does it feel to
have caught your meal? It's a whole
different level of appreciation. Yeah,
dude.
>> You know what you caught, you know what
you did to get it. And it was delicious,
too. And look,
then we're paying it forward to this
little cat right here.
Yeah.
And I tell you, this was a great day.
I'm a little sunburnt. I'm a little
sleepy. I couldn't be happier. The food
was delicious. The conversation was
great. The people were nice. I think
this is one of the better trips that
I've had and I've had a lot. So, I
recommend Taganga 10 out of 10 Joe
approved. Can't wait to see y'all here
one day.